"Previously on The Mentalist..."
Jane has worked out
that Red John is one of seven men.
"But Red John also knows
the seven names on Jane's list."
I'm gonna give you the seven names
and I need you to put a GPS bug
on each of their cell phones.
- The wires are up.
- All of them?
Yep. GPS And audio.
Okay. We watch them like hawks.
- We log everywhere they go 24/7.
- Will do.
"We have an anonymous tip
directed to your unit."
"A person or persons in distress
at 5570 West Huron."
Brett Partridge is there.
Oh, my God.
- Partridge?
- Tiger... T... Tiger.
Lisbon, finally.
"I'm sorry, Patrick."
"Teresa can't come
to the phone right now."
Sir?
Sir? Are you sure
I can't call you a cab, or...
No. You're gracious and kind.
"Domo arigato."
You're welcome.
Good night.
Oh, no.
"Pull the car over to the right."
Oh, no, no, no!
Sir, are you aware you crossed
a double yellow line back there?
Please, officer,
this is unnecessary.
- You should go.
- Have you been drinking?
No! Not at all.
Sir, I'm gonna need you
to step out of the vehicle.
Officer, I'm really sorry
about this.
Sir!
Hey, hey, don't...
Son of a...
What? It exploded?
Well, how long will it take
to get that under control?
All right, well, when the smoke clears,
let me know and I'll get a team out.
Sheridan, what happened here?
We got a call about an hour ago
from your, uh, Agent Lisbon.
Called for immediate assistance
from this address.
Uniforms responded, found
one male D.O.A. and Lisbon down.
- How is she?
- Don't know. The EMTs are with her.
- She ID the body?
- Yeah, we got a...
Brett Partridge.
Worked forensics.
- You know him?
- Uh, slightly.
- Jane, how is she?
- I don't know. You got any water on you?
- What?
- I need some water!
Anybody, you got any water?
- Bottle of water! Anybody!
- Over here!
Thank you.
Wait, wait, wait.
- Oh, hey, boss. Feeling better?
- Much. Thanks.
Good morning.
- Sir?
- Oh. Lisbon.
I'll be with you in a minute.
Lisbon...
Give me a hand, would you?
Teresa?
Sorry about this.
Everything's okay.
It's all right.
You're safe.
What happened?
You don't remember anything?
Aside from Partridge, no.
Why?
Wh-what'd he do?
Nothing.
Doctor says
you're completely unharmed
apart from a taser burn.
- What time is it?
- Morning, sometime.
Partridge is dead.
Red John killed him
and did nothing to me. Why?
He didn't do nothing.
He took Partridge's blood...
put it on your face,
made his mark.
Okay.
Wh-what does that mean?
He was just being playful.
Ran out of time.
Maybe something spooked him and
he couldn't go through his usual routine.
You were right
about the phone traces.
Red John hooked me
like a fish.
- Well, at least he threw you back.
- I'll have Van Pelt pull them down.
They're completely illegal,
aside from anything else.
There is that.
Wait. Well...
Before Partridge died,
he looked at me
and he said, "Tiger, tiger,"
as in the poem...
Which is what Red John
said to you, right?
- That's interesting.
- What does it mean?
I don't know.
Hello?
Uh, Ms. Lee? Carmen Lee?
Uh, sorry.
Wrong room, I guess.
Sorry.
Red John has been ahead of us
this entire time.
I know you say he's not psychic,
but I'm not sure.
You said yourself, when Red John
killed Eileen Turner
it was like he reached inside your head
and killed a happy memory.
How could he do that
if he's not psychic?
That's a good question.
"Hi. You've reached the voicemail
of Dr. Sophie Miller."
"If this is a true
psychiatric emergency"
"please call 911 and seek
immediate assistance."
"Otherwise, leave a message,
and I'll get back to you"
"as quickly as I can.
Thanks."
Sophie? Uh, Patrick Jane.
It's been a while.
Uh...
Good to hear your voice.
I have something I need to ask you about.
Uh, could you give me a call back
when you have a moment?
Thank you.
Hope you're well.
- How's the boss?
- Awake and cranky.
- Are they releasing her today?
- Yes, I guess.
Uh-oh. Look out.
So who's in charge
until Lisbon gets back?
- I am, sir.
- Well, no rest for the wicked, I'm afraid.
A car exploded last night
on Churchill Road.
There's one victim.
Sac P.D.'s already on the scene.
- We'll get on it.
- Yeah, I'll, uh, go with him.
I'll check with the P.D.
See what they dug up.
You, Jane?
Oh, I'm, uh, busy.
No doubt.
Well, it's good news
about Lisbon, huh?
Extraordinarily lucky
Red John sparing her.
- What was she doing there, by the way?
- What do you mean?
Well, when the call came in
about the house
there was no mention
of Partridge or Red John.
So why did Lisbon go there?
Don't know.
Following a hunch, I guess.
A hunch?
Jane, I-I understand your appetite
for secrecy.
I'm even willing to tolerate it...
within limits.
But I'm telling you again.
If you have Red John in your sights
I will be there.
Clear?
Completely.
I think it's Bertram.
We know Red John has major juice.
He has to,
given what he's pulled off.
Bertram's got more juice
than anyone on Jane's List.
No, Bret Stiles runs a worldwide cult
with thousands of followers
and billions of dollars
in assets.
Okay, other than Stiles.
But Bertram's on the inside.
He can keep an eye
on the investigation, hide his tracks.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Go ahead. Bring it on.
I don't think you're wrong.
- Yeah?
- It could definitely be Bertram.
There's something creepy
about him.
There is something creepy
about him, isn't there?
So you're, uh, agreeing with me?
- I guess.
- All right.
Wha!
The crowd goes wild
because Cho agrees with me!
Wha!
I pulled the guy over a little
before midnight. Typical D.U.I.
Driver's giving me some lip.
Then he hits the gas,
and kaboom.
- You run the plates?
- Yeah. Guy's name was Titus Stone.
I sent the ID to your office.
Coroner already took his body
but you're not missing anything.
- Guy was pretty crispy.
- Hey, Cho, look at this.
Hole in the roof
says bomb in the car.
The edges of the hole
are bent inward.
So the bomb was on the outside
on top of the car.
Yeah, but how? It doesn't look like
there was a roof rack.
- How's it stay in place?
- Did you see it explode?
No, but my dashboard
camera caught it.
You wanna see this.
Here we go.
See that thing right there?
What the hell is that?
- Run that again.
- Okay.
There's a light heading for the car
from the front.
Is that something flying there?
Looks like it hits the car
right before it explodes.
- Could it be some kinda missile?
- I doubt it.
- You know, that could be a drone.
- A drone?
- Wow, that's crazy.
- Run it again.
- Sure.
- Excuse me.
- Hey, Grace.
- Hey, good-lookin'.
So I didn't wanna wake you
when I left, but, uh...
that was pretty spectacular
last night.
Yeah, it was.
Hey, I'm free tonight.
Sounds good. So I was thinking,
uh, we should definitely discuss
the, uh, new agenda
with a focus on a significantly
new approach to... something.
- Someone just walk by?
- Yeah.
- What were you calling about?
- Uh, Titus Stone. No arrests.
No family in state. A cousin in Minneapolis.
She's been informed.
He worked for a company
called Modern Aerodynamics.
According to their website,
they design unmanned aerial vehicles.
- "You know what those are?"
- Drones?
How'd you know?
Patrick.
Dr. Miller.
Sophie.
- What's up, Cho?
- Are you working this case?
- I'm always working the case.
- Rigsby's going to the victim's house
and I've gotta talk
to some people about drones.
Drones.
That's new.
- Count me in.
- All right. Bye.
Hello. I'm Kris Makkena.
I'm one of the company's presidents.
Agent Kimball Cho, CBI.
- This is Patrick Jane.
- Hello.
I'm sorry. I'm just, uh...
It was a very hard morning.
Um... My partner is in the conference
room, if you'll come this way.
- So you make drones here?
- Uh, we design them.
- We don't manufacture.
- What did Titus Stone do for you?
Titus had been with us
since we started the company.
He was our design chief.
He was a genius. He was our genius.
He was... he was brilliant.
Mm, genius and brilliant...
usually synonyms for "difficult."
Uh, well, he was a tad eccentric
and socially awkward at times,
didn't always get people
but at the end of the day,
we all adored him.
I doubt that.
Elliott.
Elliott Winston.
I run the company with Kris.
- Agent Cho, is it?
- That's right.
Our attorney says that you think
a U.A.V. killed Titus.
- Is that true?
- U.A.V...
An unmanned vehicle.
It's a drone.
We're looking into that.
- Then why are you here?
- What do you mean?
Our product isn't very popular
in certain quarters outside the country.
Or inside the country,
for that matter.
If a U.A.V. was involved
in this, it's clear...
someone decided to use
poor Titus as a prop
in a particularly grotesque
piece of political theater
- which is simply... simply...
- Oh, Elliott...
terrorism.
The FBI should be here,
not a... state agency.
We're in contact with the FBI.
If we find evidence of terrorism
we'll take the appropriate steps.
But right now it's a homicide.
Now... was Stone having problems
with anyone else here?
Uh... nothing serious,
not that we knew about.
- What was he working on?
- He started a new line of product
uh, but he'd just completed work
on a project called the Redbird
which we delivered
to the military a few months back.
The Redbird?
Well, that's a cool name.
Is that the kind of drone
that shoots missiles
and blows up trucks
and houses, stuff?
- Something like that.
- I see.
- Redbird. Is it red?
- No. Black. What is the point here?
There is none, just that mere mention of it
makes both of you tense. Why is that?
Our work for the Pentagon is covered
by strict confidentiality agreements
so technically, admitting the Redbird exists
is a violation of federal law.
We could all go to jail
just for having this conversation.
Well, that could explain it.
Could.
Some nut out there who thinks
we're war criminals
has drawn a target on our back.
That's who you should be looking for.
Maybe.
Now where does Stone work?
This is Nicholas Vashum.
He was Titus' research assistant.
Anything else, let me know.
- Dude. Jane. Cho.
- Hey.
What's with all the bugs?
Oh, um, we've been working on U.A.Vs
that mimic insect flight
and Titus said having images
around helped.
Why would you wanna mimic
insect flight?
So you can make the drone really small
like the size of a mosquito.
It could land on your shirt
and you wouldn't even notice.
- Creepy.
- I guess.
We hear Stone can be difficult.
You have issues with him?
No. God, no. No, no.
I got him, you know?
Like, what was in Titus' head
was way more real to him
than what was outside of it.
Like... other people.
Like, he started this diet
a few months back
and if I brought in food
like, any food...
he would throw me outta the room
and say I was sabotaging him and... you know.
- You know.
- What did Stone do in his free time?
Uh, he played a lotta videogames
he watched a lotta movies.
Samurai movies, I'm thinking.
Yeah, he was really
into that kung fu stuff.
More Kurosawa than kung fu.
Was he seeing someone?
You mean, like, a woman?
Um... no.
What about hookers?
What...what makes you think
he did that?
Well, lonely overweight guy goes on a diet...
he's trying to impress someone.
Yeah, he didn't...
mention that to me.
What do you know
about the Redbird?
And you can speak freely, 'cause Cho
and I have top level security clearance.
Nothing.
I didn't work much on the Redbird.
Your boss says you get threats
from people who don't like drones.
- That true?
- Yeah. That happens. It's scary.
There's some hardcore haters
out there.
I'll bet.
I'll be outside.
If that's Stone's laptop,
I'm gonna need to take it.
Ooh, uh, I'll have to ask.
It probably has some
classified material on there.
You guys really have
top security clearance?
No.
"Hi. You've reached the voicemail
of Dr. Sophie Miller."
"If this is a true
psychiatric emergency"
"please call 911 and seek
immediate assistance."
"Otherwise, leave a message,
and I'll get back to you"
"as quickly as I can."
Grace, I want you to stop what you're doing
and look up an address for me.
We ran Stone's credit cards.
Jane was right.
He was hiring prostitutes through an escort
service called Private Companion.
You get any names?
Yeah, a woman named Carol Mathews
was with Stone the night before he died.
- Rigsby's bringing her in.
- And what about the laptop?
Any problems
with security clearance?
No, we told the FBI we only wanted to look
at his calendar and correspondence.
They're cool with it.
Van Pelt's on it.
- When are you getting out?
- Soon, I hope.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Man, they're letting anybody
into the hospital these days.
- Ray.
- Hey, Teresa.
Sorry about this.
What are you doing here?
Well, I heard that my favorite CBI agent
was laid up. I thought I'd stop by.
Oh. Thanks.
Nice suit.
Private sector's treating you all right.
Yeah. I do okay.
- So what happened?
- Oh, nothing.
I...
I scraped my knee.
That's not what I hear.
I hear you were this close
to Red John.
That's some scary stuff.
You okay?
Fine. Yeah, it turns out
Red John isn't so tough.
You know, he barely
laid a hand on me.
Good for you.
Well, th-thanks for...
for coming by. But I'm fine.
I'm... totally fine.
Am I making you
nervous somehow?
- No.
- You sure?
'Cause you're acting
like I'm making you nervous.
No!
Wh-why are you here?
You and Jane figure you're pretty close
to catching Red John, right?
Have you got a bead on him,
parameters?
Can't say. Sorry.
Why do you care?
I don't care.
I have clients who care.
Visualize clients.
Why do they care?
You know, I figured this was how
the conversation was gonna go, but...
I came anyway.
You know why?
I like you, Teresa.
I really do.
And one of these days,
you and me...
We'll have a time.
Take care of yourself.
I've gotta get outta here.
Miss Mathews, I don't care
about the prostitution charges.
I'm just interested in what happened
with Titus Stone.
I get it.
You work as an escort for the...
Private Companion Agency,
is that right?
Strictly speaking,
I'm a, independent contractor.
That means the company offers
the service
but the terms are negotiated
between the client and me.
Also, they don't pay withholding
or F.I.C.A. taxes.
And Stone was paying
for you to sleep with him?
- That is what was occurring.
- How long had you known Stone?
Like, four months?
He'd call every two, three weeks.
And how would you describe him?
Quiet, not very good
at talking, really.
Not until he got into the role.
- The role?
- Yeah, he's into role-playing.
Oh. And what role did you play?
He's a samurai warrior, and I'm a village
girl he just saved from bandits.
He had a robe and sandals
and a real samurai sword.
It's called a katana.
He would talk about the honorable way
of the warrior
and then I would be grateful
for about a half hour.
What was it? Go on.
You know, when he was talking
about honor in that crazy robe
it's the only time he ever really seemed
comfortable with himself.
You saw him the night
before last, right?
Did he talk about any issues
that he had
- problems with other people in his life?
- No.
He did seem kind of sad, though.
He paid for an extra half hour.
Just, you know, cuddling.
- Grace.
- Boss.
- They let you go?
- Y-yeah. What is that?
A computer from Stone's office.
- Anything on it?
- No, nothing.
No files, no applications.
Even the operating system is gone.
It's been wiped.
- Well, how would you do that?
- You run a program.
But you have to run it five or six times
to a get a disk this clean.
Somebody really wanted to get rid
of something on the drive.
There are fragments of data
here and there.
- I'm trying to put 'em together.
- Keep checking, and, um, Grace...
the surveillance
on the Red John suspects...
- I need you to take it down.
- Really?
Right away, as soon as you can.
Don't leave anything behind.
- Sure. Okay.
- Have you seen Jane?
No. He called a little while ago
needed an address.
Whose address?
Lisbon. You're wondering
who Sophie Miller is?
"She was your psychiatrist
after your wife died."
What made you think of her?
Oh, I don't know.
Doctors, hospitals.
You think Red John learned
about Eileen Turner from her.
He must have.
I must've told her a lotta things
I don't remember.
I was on some serious medication.
Well, call me after you talk to her.
- Sure.
- Right after.
Bye.
"The patient showed some treatment
response at the session."
"Hilary continues to exhibit signs
of separation anxiety disorder."
"Her symptoms..."
Oh! Oh!
Boss?
Are you okay?
Jane found a dead body.
It was somebody he knows.
Red John killed her.
- Why?
- We think he got information from her.
Jane's talking to the local P.D.
Uh, did you get something
off Stone's computer?
This is the other thing.
I was shutting down
the surveillance like you asked
and I noticed something.
I wasn't looking for it.
It was just there.
It's really weird.
It's happening right now.
And when was the last time
you talked to her?
Uh, a-about five years ago.
Excuse me.
Lisbon, I have to call you back.
Jane, I thought you should know.
Three of the Red John suspects
are here together right now.
- Who?
- Bertram
Sheriff McAllister,
and Reede Smith.
They're talking outside
Bertram's office.
And we'll need to track the arrests.
Hello.
Uh, Jane, what you doing?
This is a private meeting.
How was I to know?
Door was closed.
- Agent Smith.
- Jane.
- Sheriff McAllister.
- Tom.
Tom.
Okay, I'll call you Tom then.
So what's the deal, Patrick?
Well, as soon as you're done,
I need to talk with you.
Well, we may be some time.
We're discussing
a joint anti-narcotics effort
by the CBI,
the FBI, and Napa County.
A lotta meth in my neck of the woods.
I'd like to see it cleaned up.
Good luck with that.
Uh, carry on discussing your effort.
I'll wait.
So what is it that you would
like to talk about, Jane?
You wanted to know whenever we made
progress on the Red John case.
We've made progress.
Red John just killed the doctor who
treated me during my nervous breakdown.
Maybe... you and I should
discuss this alone.
Well, we're all law enforcement
family here, right?
Sophie Miller. Good woman.
He chopped her head off, placed it
in her kitchen oven.
- A gag, I suppose.
- Dear God.
So how is that progress?
Red John killed Sophie Miller
because I'm closing in on him.
He's killed two people
within days now.
He's getting desperate
and a little crazy
and he doesn't realize, but he's made
a terrible mistake.
- That's progress, right?
- What mistake did he make?
I would tell you, but I've always gotten
the feeling that this room is bugged.
Wired.
Good seeing you all.
Now what the hell was that
all about?
Exactly how much
does Jane know?
- Well, that is the question, isn't it?
- Yes, it is.
- And it's your job to know the answer.
- I'm doing my best.
Thank you.
So did you see anything that says
one of them is Red John?
No.
I'm sorry about Sophie.
I know she helped you.
Do you wanna be alone?
I'm gonna go back to my office.
- You can come...
- No, no, wait, wait.
I'm waiting.
Red John killed Sophie
because she could identify him.
Now he could've stolen my records
without ever seeing her.
He must have wanted
to meet her, to talk to her.
- Why?
- Well, I don't know why.
Maybe curious about someone
that was close to me.
But he did.
He's been planning this
for a while.
Probably went to see her weeks ago
or maybe even months.
Why not kill her then?
And why kill her now?
Her death would've tipped me off.
He waited until he knew
that I would try to track her down.
He had to have used subterfuge
to get in to see her.
- Like pretend to be a patient?
- Probably.
Then she'd have a file on him.
What good would it be?
It's not like he's gonna tell her the truth.
No, but Sophie had
a very good eye for people.
He may not have been able
to hide everything from her.
We need to get that file.
The local police will let you
into Miller's house.
Her appointment calendar
should be in her office.
You're looking
for a first-time male patient
that's been to see her once or twice
in the past six months.
- Got it.
- Do not tell anyone what you're doing.
Turn off your cell phone
and the GPS in your car.
- You don't know who's watching.
- Okay. If you say so.
What's up? Did you find
something on Stone's computer?
I'll have something soon.
Cho wanted me to tell you that he went
to talk to a guy named Aaron Kalinosky.
Worked for Modern Aerodynamics
until a few months ago.
What's the connection there?
Apparently he's got a lawsuit
against Titus Stone.
- Aaron Kalinosky?
- Uh, just a moment, please.
Give it a run.
- Agent Cho, yes?
- Yes.
- That one of your designs?
- Yeah. It's, uh, self-guided.
It's supposed to wend its way
through the forest
and return
without smashing into a tree.
We'll see if it pulls it off.
- This about Titus Stone?
- Yes.
Poor bastard.
The man was brilliant.
Head and shoulders
above the rest.
Did a samurai kill him?
Sorry. Bad taste.
I understand you were suing him
and Modern Aerodynamics.
Oh, that.
I worked with Titus, Kris, and Elliott
on several projects while I was there.
We were arguing over who owns one
of the designs they're still developing
happens all the time.
Nothing personal.
Did Titus Stone feel that way?
- You're gonna have to ask him.
- Were you friends with him?
I don't know that he had friends.
We got along.
Did you talk to him recently?
- Um...
- Why don't you wanna tell me?
'Cause it's confidential,
and national security and blah, blah, blah.
Here.
Try not to get me arrested
for saying this, okay?
Titus called six weeks ago.
There was trouble with that system
they sold to the military.
The Redbird.
There was an accident
in Afghanistan.
One of the Redbirds missed a target
and hit a civilian home
and there were nine or ten deaths,
big investigation.
Titus was worried that there was
a problem with the guidance system.
He wanted me to look
at the specs with him.
Then... he called back
a few days later.
False alarm.
Everything was fine.
Uh... look out.
See? No hands.
No one will say anything official
about the Redbird.
I talked to a guy I served with
who's at the Pentagon now.
He said, off the record there was
an accident and an investigation.
Apparently it cleared
Modern Aerodynamics.
They think the accident
was caused by local weather.
I guess that's why Stone
called Kalinosky off.
What else do we have?
The techs found fragments
of a drone like this in the wreckage.
It's for surveillance.
No weapons.
But you could attach
a small explosive to it.
- Is that easy to do?
- Nah.
Had to be somebody
who knew what they were doing.
- Co-worker?
- With the added weight
the drone has a range of 4 or 5 miles.
I checked with the other employees.
No one was close enough
that night to launch it.
Yeah, maybe Elliott Winston was right.
Some anti-drone guy did it.
Okay, you know what?
Let's start over.
What did Stone do that night?
Well, he left his house
about 6:30.
Went somewhere.
We don't know where.
Showed up at the restaurant 8:15.
Stayed until 11:50.
A 3-hour dinner by himself?
That's a meal.
Did you get anything
from the computer?
Yeah, but it's just a stream
of numbers.
- I can't make sense of it.
- Well, find somebody who can.
Otherwise, we're back
to the drone people.
Did we get the autopsy report?
- You wanna look at the autopsy results?
- Come on. Don't be so surprised.
Does it say what Stone
had for dinner?
Um... "Contents of stomach."
"Fried chicken, cheeseburger
mashed potatoes"
"French fries, macaroni and cheese
apple pie, and ice cream."
- Yuck.
- Excellent.
Let's bring everyone in tomorrow,
wrap this one up.
- What does that mean?
- Finish.
Uh, move on, concern ourselves
with something more important.
- You know who did it?
- Sure.
Take a look for yourselves.
It's right there.
Where?
Thank you for coming.
This shouldn't take long.
What is all this? Is...
is that Aaron Kalinosky?
- Ah, we'll...
- What's he doing here?
Let you know in a minute.
Please, sit down.
I'm sure you're nervous
called to see the Coppers and all
so, uh, let me reassure you
we know neither of you killed Titus Stone.
I think I speak for both of us
when I say that's true.
- Do you know who did it?
- Yes.
- He killed himself.
- He what?
He was a samurai, and he felt
he'd dishonored himself
so he committed seppuku...
ritual suicide
with his own particular sword.
- Well, what's your evidence?
- His dinner.
Cheeseburger, fried chicken
mashed potatoes,
mac and cheese.
Comfort food.
A condemned man's last meal.
Why would he do that?
H-how had he dishonored himself?
Miss Makkena, you wanna tell us?
- Me? Why?
- Because he told you.
- Uh, no.
- Sure, he did.
He came to you to confess
because he was in love with you.
Kris.
I brought you this.
I thought
I-I won't need it anymore.
- Can I come in?
- Uh, yeah...sure.
- Okay, Titus didn't love me.
- Sure, he did.
He had a photograph of you
on his desk.
He kept it there.
He also hired a hooker that looked exactly
like you. It wasn't hard to see.
He came because he knew
there was a problem with Redbird.
It's what led to those deaths
and you three covered it up.
You made investigators think
it was something else
but he couldn't live with that.
- People died because we screwed up.
- Okay.
There were mistakes.
We all know it.
We lied! To everyone!
- It's not... It isn't honorable.
- I don't even know what that means.
Look, it was a moment.
Okay? That's it.
The point is to collect ourselves
act with grace, and move on
because if we don't
Titus, this company...it's gone.
Me, too. I am done.
You will have ruined me.
- Is that what you wanna do, Titus?
- No.
He told you
what he was gonna do
and you didn't even try
and talk him out of it.
The way I feel right now,
I can't live with myself.
I think you should do
whatever brings you peace.
Who knows?
It could be beautiful.
"So you went to the office"
"and you found the suicide note
on his computer"
"that he told you about,
and you got rid of it."
- Kris... Is this true?
- Look, shut up, Elliott.
- Look, even if it were true...
- I had no idea about Titus, none.
- Even if it were, you can't prove it.
- I'm gonna be sick.
Look, just shut up, okay?
I-I-I have...
- I have nothing to answer for.
- You're right.
We can't prove anything.
Not about the suicide.
- But we can prove the cover-up.
- What do you mean?
Agent Van Pelt was able to recover
documents from Stone's computer.
They're just numbers to us
but according to Mr. Kalinosky
they prove that there were flaws
in Redbird's design.
He's out there right now
about to give his statement.
- No.
- Obstruction of justice, fraud
- maybe even manslaughter.
- That's impossible!
- I wiped that disk.
- That sounds like a confession.
- It does, doesn't it?
- I'm done.
Wait, wait. Elliott, hang on. Look,
everything's gonna be all right if we just...
- If we just hang together.
- Hang together? Hang...
Are you insane?
- After what you did to Titus?
- Just don't focus on the negative.
Focus on this. I'm calling my lawyer
and cutting a deal.
You're on your own, Kris.
Good luck.
- I wiped the disk.
- You're right. You did.
Mr. Kalinosky said the data
was just random numbers.
- Gibberish.
- Oops.
Jane, Rigsby's on the phone.
Oh. Okay. Excuse me.
I'll take it in your office.
Miss Makkena, I can't arrest you today
but I will... soon.
- How many names?
- Four.
Ernest Matthewson,
Mitchell Livingston Washburn
- Miguel Vavario, and Jay Roth.
- Roth.
It's from the German rot.
Means "red".
- When did she see him?
- Uh...
About five and a half months ago.
- Do you have the file?
- No. There is no file.
What do you mean?
"Well, I searched the whole office.
It's not here."
I got the department secretary to check
the archived files at the university.
There's no file there, either.
It's gone.
- He took it.
- I'm sorry, Jane.
Oh, it's all right, Rigsby.
Thanks for everything.
We'll see you when you get back.
- Damn it!
- Now, now.
I thought we had something.
I really did.
- Why aren't you more upset?
- Well, I kinda half-expected it.
And I know something
that Red John doesn't.
Sophie dictated her notes.
She couldn't type. Never learned.
She was kinda proud
of the fact.
She had a service that transcribed
everything for her.
- Did they keep a copy?
- Very possibly.
"Preliminary diagnostic
session with Jay Roth."
"Mr. Roth came in complaining of a recent
issue with severe acrophobia."
- Fear of heights.
- I know.
"He's middle-aged, in good health"
"with no stated prior history
of psychiatric issues."
"He has no living family,
but many friends"
"on whom he relies for company
and emotional support."
"He's well-spoken,
good posture, self-possessed."
"In the waiting room, he sat calmly
in one place needing no distraction."
"Though I note,
he is an excellent whistler."
"His self-presentation is pleasant"
"but there are hints in his behavior
of a damaged and narcissistic personality."
"He says he deals with conflict
and adversity easily, though."
"I'm not convinced
he's being truthful about this."
"In fact, much of what he said,
though spoken convincingly"
"did not match what I can only call
my instinctive response to his presence"
"though I cannot point to identifiable
clinical behaviors that indicate this."
"I sense something deceptive
and dark in his emotional makeup."
"However, there is every indication
that his phobia issues are real..."
"whether acrophobia or some
other phobia remains to be seen."
"An interesting case."
"I look forward to further sessions
with him."